Max M. Jackson, M.Ed.

520-260-1294 | maxj@email.arizona.edu 1847 N. Frances Blvd. | Tucson, AZ 85712

Executive Summary

Experienced Undergraduate Admissions and Student Affairs professional with 12 years of skill in an administrative and leadership capacity, within a university setting. Proficient counseling students, who learn differently, about college admission. Conscientious of recruitment, admission, enrollment, retention, and professional development initiatives within the field of Higher Education.

Work Experience

Sep. 2012 – present: The University of Arizona SALT Center, Admission and Recruitment Coordinator, Admission and New Student Enrollment

- Coordinate the application process in a paperless administrative environment
- Update the SALT Center website's application and recruitment event information regularly
- Determine whether applications are ready for admission review; interview applicants as needed
- Read learning disability documentation and make SALT Center admission decisions
- Ensure all post-acceptance enrollment steps are completed by candidates
- Co-coordinate and co-facilitate SALT Center Enrollment Events (Orientation)
- Manage Waiting List process and related communications
- Collaborate with Student Affairs Systems Group (SASG) to build, test, and deploy enrollment data reporting tools
- Suggest, deploy, and test enhancements for two SALT Center online applications with SASG
- Meet with prospective students frequently for general information sessions
- Represent SALT Center browse tables at national and local events
- Conduct general information presentations at the SALT Center, on campus, or at high schools
- Mentor 15 SALT Center Student Ambassadors
- Identify Ambassador work opportunities, compile monthly work lists, and hold monthly team meetings
- Participate monthly on the College Relations and Orientation Advisory committees
- Attend SALT Center Scholarship, Marketing, and the SSRI, Diversity and Inclusion committee meetings

May 2011 – Sep. 2012: University of Arizona Office of Undergraduate Admissions Recruitment Office Specialist, Call Center Supervisor

- Supervised and mentored a staff of 28-30
- Directed a high-volume, inbound and outbound, thirteen-line call center
- Chaired a hiring committee to hire new staff
- Trained staff for phone calls to assist new applicants through the admission process
- Provided feedback and professional development opportunities for staff as needed
- Managed the call center calendar of staff schedules
- Transferred, directed, and answered questions over the phone as appropriate
- Answered questions over IM and in-person from staff and the general public
- Investigated complex application, document processing and website questions

Aug. 2006 – May 2011: University of Arizona Office of Undergraduate Admissions Processing Credentials Evaluator, Sr.

- Examined and evaluated both high school and college-level coursework of students applying for undergraduate admission, determining if students met UA's undergraduate criteria or guidelines
- Provided Transfer Credit Articulation support for the Office of the Registrar
- Communicated routinely with the Office of the Registrar regarding pre-1988 coursework and access to archived record information
- Engaged with Re-Admit applicants to determine if they left in good standing and if coursework taken outside UA satisfied admission guidelines in a major based on that college's Re-Admit criteria.

Oct. 2002 – May 2006: Teletech Facilities Management, Tucson, AZ UPS Preferred Customer Associate

• Served as a corporate liaison for preferred account holders with UPS; some of whom were Fortune 500 companies

- Tracked shipments, provided billing adjustments, traced lost packaged, initiated loss/damage claims
- Built customer loyalty by making conscientious efforts to understand each account holder's unique service needs, communication style, and distinctive business processes

Education

Jun. 2016 – Present: Northern Arizona University (In-progress)

Doctor of Education in Educational Leadership (Community College/ Higher Ed. focus)

Jan. 2012 – May 2016: Northern Arizona University

Master of Education in Educational Leadership (Community College/ Higher Ed. focus)

Jan. 2006 – Dec. 2011: The University of Arizona

Bachelor of Arts in Art History

Aug. 2000 – Dec. 2001: Eastern Arizona College

Undecided - General Education

Professional Skills and Knowledge

Highly educated about: University Student Affairs, Dean of Students code of conduct, and FERPA

- Eleven years of experience with Undergraduate Admission, Recruitment, and Credentials Evaluation
- Keen acumen regarding Neuropsychological Evaluations, IEPs, 504 Plans, and various other learning disability testing, statements, documentation, and learning and attention challenges at large
- PeopleSoft and CRM Technolutions (Slate) systems expertise
- Supervisory experience and the ability to manage a high volume of email
- Transfer Credit Articulation knowledge
- Event planning and coordination
- Public speaking capability via working at: college fairs, high school events, symposiums, and conferences
- Informed on processes surrounding business travel, including expenses, authorizations, and motor pool procedures
- Experienced with building security measures and emergency response procedures

Leadership Attributes

- Clifton Strengths, (Signature Themes): Input, Strategic, Achiever, Individualization, Communication
- Belbin Team Inventory Method:
 - Action-Oriented Role: 'Implementer,' Able to translate ideas into concrete tasks and implements them
 - · People-Oriented Role: 'Team Worker,' Co-operative, mild, perceptive, diplomatic, builder, averts friction
 - Cerebral Role: 'Plant,' Unorthodox, imaginative person with an independent outlook

Professional Associations

- Learning Disabilities Association (LDA)
- National Association for College Admission Counselors (NACAC)
- Rocky Mountain Association for College Admission Counselors (RMACAC)

References

Jeremiah Webb, Years Known: 12 Senior Academic Advisor II The University of Arizona College of Humanities P.O. Box 210067 Tucson, AZ 85721 520-621-1048 jaw@email.arizona.edu Deb Evano, Years Known: 6 Administrative Associate The University of Arizona SALT Center 1010 North Highland Avenue Tucson, AZ 85721 520-626-0975 evanod@email.arizona.edu Dr. Rudy M. Molina, Jr. Years Known: 5
Associate Vice Chancellor University of IL, Chicago Student Affairs
1200 West Harrison Street Chicago, IL 60607
312-996-7000
rumo@uic.edu